Guide to the Thain White Papers 1877-1983
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula,
Thain White Papers
1877-1983
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, Montana 59812 406-243-2053 https://www.umt.edu/library/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 137
White, Thain, 1913-1999
5.5 linear feet
Thain White was a Montana historian who focused on the history of western Montana, particularly the Flathead valley. The collection contains maps, artifacts, and documents concerning a variety of Montana historical topics.
Biographical Note
Thain White was born and raised in Rollins, Montana. White spent his early years helping his father, Ernie White, raise sheep at White's Columbia Sheep Company. It was during these years that White acquired a strong interest in the history and archeology of his native state. This interest resulted in decades of Montana historical research and writings.
In 1949, Thain and Ernie White began the Flathead Lake Lookout Museum in Lakeside, Montana. Located on the west shore of Flathead Lake, the museum is dedicated to exhibitions and collections concerning regional and primitive artifacts. Two generations of the White family maintained the museum facility until 1972, when the O'Neil Jones family purchased the museum.
During his years as museum director, White undertook a number of research projects concerning the Montana area and the Flathead Valley in particular. He conducted a variety of excavations at battlegrounds from the Indian Wars of the 1880s and homestead sites such as Chimney Coulee. He also focused much of his research on railroads and stage companies existing in Montana at the turn of the century. Much of White's work was done in partnership with Montana State University (now University of Montana) Professor of Anthropology Carling I. Malouf. White documented his research and many of his articles were published together with Malouf by the Flathead Lake Lookout Museum.
Mr. White died on April 29, 1999.
The collection contains maps, artifacts, and documents concerning a variety of Montana historical topics. Much of the collection is composed of unpublished copies of White's historical articles, as well as notes and research material. White documented and photographed many of his excavations and artifacts and these photos compose a large portion of the collection. The Thain White Papers provide a range of original research on many popular Montana subjects.
The collection is divided into eight series, two with additional subseries:
Series I: Correspondence, 0.1 linear feet, 1915, 1953-1965
Series II: White's Publications, 1.2 linear feet, 1959-1983
Subseries 1: Indian Wars, 0.3 linear feet, 1960-1976
Subseries 2: Other Native American Studies, 0.2 linear feet, 1959-1976
Subseries 3: Forts, 0.1 linear feet, 1960-1962 and undated
Subseries 4: Homesteading, 0.2 linear feet, 1967-1975
Subseries 5: Flathead Valley, 0.1 linear feet, 1960-1969
Subseries 6: Other Publications, 0.3 linear feet, 1962-1978
Series III: Research Material, 0.2 linear feet, undated
Series IV: Other Publications, 0.2 linear feet, 1970-1978
Series V: Newspaper Clippings, 2 folders, 1955-1968
Series VI: Maps, 1 folder, 1939
Series VII: Artifacts, 1.0 linear feet and 2 folders, 1906-1960
Series VIII: Photographs, 2.75 linear feet, 1877-1982
Subseries 1: General, 1.25 linear feet, 1889-1979
Subseries 2: Boats and Planes, 0.4 linear feet, 1905-1982
Subseries 3: Soldiers, Indians,and Cowboys, 0.6 linear feet, 1877-1911
Subseries 4: Nature and Animals, 0.2 linear feet, 1898-1973
Subseries 5: European, 0.2 linear feet, 1914-1978
Subseries 6: Going-to-the-Sun Highway, 0.1 linear feet, circa 1931
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
Gift of Thain White, date unknown.
During 1999 processing, the following items were transferred to the Map Division of the Mansfield Library:
Map of the Townsite of Demersville, December 28, 1888.
Map of the Battle of the Bear's Paw. March 28, 1936. Survey by C.R. Noyes. Depicts camps, rifle pits and death points.
Original survey map of the Battle of the Bear's Paw. Drawn in 1935. Survey by C.R. Noyes, staking and point of interest by LV McLohorter, Chief Many Wounds and Chief White Hawk, drawn by Thain White.
Archaeologists--Montana--Lake County; Historians--Montana--Lake County
Coaching--Montana--History; Frontier and pioneer life--Montana; Indians of North America--Montana--Antiquities; Railroads--Montana--History
Flathead River Valley (B.C. and Mont.)--History; Montana--Antiquities; Montana--History; Montana--History, Military--19th century
Flathead Lake Lookout Museum (Lakeside, Mont.)
Malouf, Carling I. (Carling Isaac), 1916-2007
Photographs; Maps; Artifacts
Montana; Artifacts; Maps; Photographs; Native Americans; Pioneers; Transportation
- Correspondence, 1915, 1953-1965; Series I; 0.1 linear feet
  A few personal letters, including correspondence between White and Professor Carling Malouf, are contained in this series. Also included is a letter from the Scandinavian-American Hide and Metal Company dated 1915.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Other Correspondence: Letter from Scandinavian-American Hide and Metal Co., 1915 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Other Correspondence, 1960-1987 (Box-folder 1/3)
- White's Publications, 1959-1983; Series II; 1.2 linear feet
  Articles on a variety of Montana historical topics constitute this series. White writes on his original research and the collection contains typed, handwritten and published copies. Many of these works were done with the assistance of Professor Carling Malouf. A few of the original copies also include maps and artifacts concerning the research topic. The series is subdivided into six subseries: Indian Wars, Other Native American Studies, Forts, Homesteading, Flathead Valley History and Other Montana Studies. Within these subdivisions, the articles are then arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - List of White Manuscripts, compiled by Malouf, 1983 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Subseries 1: Indian Wars, 1960-1976; 0.3 linear feet
    This subseries contains White's writing and research concerning the armed conflicts between Native American tribes in the Northwest and the United States government.
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield 1877, artifacts, Book One, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield 1877, artifacts, Book Two, undated (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield 1877, artifacts, Book Two, Section Two, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield 1877, artifacts, Book Two, Section Two and additions, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Bighole Battlefield, 1877, relics, 1962 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Nez Perce War 1877, Clearwater Battlefield, 1960 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Nez Perce War 1877, relics from Misery Hill, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Nez Perce War 1877, possible site of Rains Scouting Party Tragedy, 1960 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Nez Perce War 1877, site were seven Nez Perce warriors were killed, 1969 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Battle of the Rosebud 1976, artifacts, undated (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Battle of Wolf Mountain, 1877, a visit to the sit in 1963 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Other Native American Studies, 1959-1976; Subseries 2; 0.2 linear feet
    This subseries contains White's writing and research on various aspects of Native American culture.
    - Sheep Herder's Dictionary of Blackfeet Indian Words, undated (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Buffalo Drives on the Blackfeet Indian Reservation, undated (Box-folder 1/17)
    - A Study of a Few Indian Canoes, 1976 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - A Study of a Few Indian Canoes, Part Two, 1976 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Lewis and Clark's Trail: Exploration of a Segment of the Northern Nez Perce Trail, 1975 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Early Kutenai History, undated (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Firsts Among the Kutenai, undated (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Kutenai Place Names of the Flathead Lake Region in NW MT, undated (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Sketches of Indian Pictograms, undated (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Location of Pipestone (Indian) Quarry: NW MT, Pleasant Valley, undated (Box-folder 2/8)
    - A Search for the Site of Sitting Bull; Where He Spent the First Winter in Canada After the Custer Massacre", 1960 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Tipi Rings in the Flathead Lake Area, 1959 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Forts, 1960-1962 and undated; Subseries 3; 0.1 linear feet
    This subseries contains White's writing and research on various trading posts and military forts.
    - Fort Belknap, 1960 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Fort Conrad, undated (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Some Observations as the Site of Fort C.J. Smith, 1962 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - A Study of Some Fort Owen Window Glass, undated (Box-folder 2/14)
    - The Possible Location of Saleesh House, December 1960 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - A Partial List of Montana Forts, Posts, Trading Posts, undated (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Homesteading, 1967-1975; Subseries 4; 0.2 linear feet
    This subseries contains White's research and writing on various homesteading sites.
    - A Visit to Chimney Coulee, 1967 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - A Second Visit to Chimney Coulee, 1968 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - The 1974 Visit to Chimney Coulee (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Another Visit to Chimney Coulee, 1974 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Some Explorations at Chimney Coulee, 1975 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - The Billings Homestead Window Glass: Comparison to Fort Owen Window Glass, undated (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Flathead Valley, 1960-1969; Subseries 5; 0.1 linear feet
    This subseries contains White's research and writing on the Flathead Valley in northwest Montana.
    - Medicine Rock, 1960 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Brief History of the Steamboating on Flathead Lake, 1967 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - A Study of the Lithograph "Flathead Lake, Looking Southward" in Pacific Railroad Reports and Surveys 1853-1854, 1968 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Buffalo Soldiers in the Flathead Valley 1890, 1969; Discusses troops of African American soldiers at Fort Missoula. Also refers to the Demersville soldiers. (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Beautiful Flathead - America's Finest Lake, undated (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Stagecoaches, Flathead Lake, undated (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Other Publications, 1962-1978; Subseries 6; 0.3 linear feet
    This subseries contains White's writing and research on various historic figures and topics.
    - Artifact From the Location Where J. M. Dunn was Murdered, 1962 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Big Game Perches, undated (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Livestock Brands Used on the Reservations in Montana by Indians and Whites before 1900, 1970 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - List of Pre-Historic and Historic Sites, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Captain William Logan, Biography, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Medals, undated (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Relics From the "Rifle Pits" of the Yellowstone Wagon Road and Prospecting Expedition of 1874, undated (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Scarred Trees in Western MT, undated (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Excerpt From the Manuscript by Mary Elizabeth Story Howard, typescript of a 1902 manuscript (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Sixty Years Later, (picture comparison of Europe in 1917 and 1978) (Box-folder 3/9)
- Research Material, undated; Series III; 0.2 linear feet
  This series is composed of a variety of notes and research documents on Montana territory forts and Montana stagecoaches. These works were reference materials for White or unfinished projects. None of this material is dated.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Notes on Old Forts, undated (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Research Material: Stagecoaches, general, undated (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Research Material: Benton Line, undated (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Research Material: Monida - Yellowstone Stage, undated (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Research Material: Overland Freight Line, undated (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Research Material: Pine Butte, undated (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Research Material: Redrock, Salmon and Gibbonsville Stage Co. (Includes advertisements), undated (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Research Material: Redrock, Salmon and Gibbonsville Stage Co., undated (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Research Material: Thunder Mountain, undated (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Research Material: Yankee Fork, undated (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Research Material: Demersville, undated (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Research Material: Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 3/21)
- Other Publications, 1970-1978; Series IV; 0.2 linear feet
  This small series includes a 1970 publication on steamboats as well as a 1978 tabloid from the Flathead Lookout Museum. The series also contains a few publications on various historical topics.
  - Steamboat Bill, Number 114, Summer, 1970 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Flathead Lake Lookout Museum Tabloid, 1978 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Other Publications, undated (Box-folder 4/3)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1955-1968; Series V
  White collected a few clippings from Montana newspapers on topics of his interest.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Newspaper article spread, composed of articles from the 1870s from a variety of Montana newspapers, (courtesy of the MT Historical Society), undated (Box-folder 4/5)
- Maps, 1939; Series VI; 1 folder
  This series consists of a 1939 map of a motor passenger boat for Great Northern Railway and an undated map of a machinery floor plan from the Eureka Lumber Co.
  - Maps, 1939 and undated (Box-folder 4/6)
- Artifacts, 1906-1960; Series VII; 1.0 linear feet and 2 folders
  This series includes impressions and tombstone rubbings, a sample of early twentieth-century sheep and pig tags and a display of materials used to make Indian canoes.
  - Impression of an aluminum disk, like the one found at Medicine Rock, 1960 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Tombstone rubbing from the possible site of the Rains scouting party tragedy, undated (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Sheep and pig tags (Ernest White collection), 1906-1908 (Box OS 5)
  - Display of Indian canoe materials, from Golden Lake, Ontario, undated (Box OS 5)
- Photographs, 1877-1976; Series VIII; 2.75 linear feet; 758 photographs
  Many of White's articles also included photographs of excavations or relics. Most of these photos were taken by White, although some are prints from the National Archives or the Montana Historical Society. A separation sheet has been included within the collection for those photos that have been removed from White's articles. The photographs include images of a wide variety of Montana subjects, including artifacts, historical places and people, animals and plants, and Glacier National Park. A set of European photos includes images of France and Belgium in the late 1970s.
  The photos are divided into six subseries, based on White's arrangement: General; Boats and Planes; Soldiers, Indians, and Cowboys; Nature and Animals; European; and Going-to-the-Sun Highway. The photos have two types of numbers on them, but are intellectually arranged by subject.
  - General, 1889-1979; Subseries 1; 1.25 linear feet; 366 photos
    This subseries contains various photographs, many taken by Thain White, that relate to his research and writing; many are Montana subjects.
    - Mountain Inn, near Somers, Montana (x2), circa 1906; 137(VIII):1
    - Somers Lumber Mill (x2), circa 1913; 137(VIII):2
    - Residence of H.M. Hill, founder of Clancy, Montana (x3), May 1895; 137(VIII):3
    - Lump City, Montana, May 1895; 137(VIII):4
    - People outside General Store in Lump City, Montana, circa 1906; 137(VIII):5
    - Field near Clancy, Montana, 1895; 137(VIII):6
    - People standing around an old tractor, circa 1920; 137(VIII):7
    - Piegan sweat house near Browning, Montana, September 1900; 137(VIII):8
    - Bird's eye view of Missoula, Montana (used on postcard), 1910; 137(VIII):9
    - Town of Hartford, Montana, May 1895; 137(VIII):10
    - Great Tycoon Rock, near Lump City, Montana, May 1895; 137(VIII):11
    - Map of Lump Gulch Mining District, May 1895; 137(VIII):12
    - Old Pioneer Store at Clancy, Montana, May 1895; 137(VIII):13
    - Somers, Montana, circa 1906; 137(VIII):14
    - John O'Brien's Mill, circa 1904; 137(VIII):15
    - Somers Tie Plant, circa 1905; 137(VIII):16
    - Somers Tie Plant from Glacier National Park, 1979; 137(VIII):17
    - Gordon Pouliot studies at smoking lodge, October 1960; 137(VIII):18
    - Pouliot at smoking lodge, October 1960; 137(VIII):19
    - Near George Tinker's house, October 1960; 137(VIII):20
    - Rifle barricades near smoking lodge, October 1960; 137(VIII):21
    - Rifle shelter, looking north, October 1960; 137(VIII):22
    - Close view of ranch, October 1960; 137(VIII):23
    - Clearwater Battlefield cartridges, 1960; 137(VIII):24
    - Clearwater Battlefield cartridges, 1960; 137(VIII):25
    - Horse shoe, 1960; 137(VIII):26
    - William Foster grave marker, 1960; 137(VIII):27
    - Foster marker looking Northwest, 1960; 137(VIII):28
    - Virgil Schmidt at believed site of Lt. Rains and five companions' death, 1960; 137(VIII):29
    - Schmidt pointing to army bullets, 1960; 137(VIII):30
    - Two loaded, unfired bullets, 1960; 137(VIII):31
    - Inscription on monument in memory of Indian casualties, 1962; 137(VIII):32
    - Tomb site, Big Hole Battlefield, Montana, 1962; 137(VIII):33
    - Big Hole Battlefield National Monument, Montana, 1962; 137(VIII):34
    - Big Hole Battlefield National Monument, Montana, 1962; 137(VIII):35
    - General area of Nez Perce camp, 1951; 137(VIII):36
    - Campsite, 1962; 137(VIII):37
    - Campsite, 1962; 137(VIII):38
    - Remains of bridge, 1962; 137(VIII):39
    - Location of fired cartridges, 1962; 137(VIII):40
    - Powder Horn, 1962; 137(VIII):41
    - Remington Rolling Block Rifle, 1962; 137(VIII):42
    - Seven cartridges from Big Hole, 1962; 137(VIII):43
    - Big Hole spur, 1962; 137(VIII):44
    - Big Hole spur, 1962; 137(VIII):45
    - Relics from siege area and Indian camp area of Big Hole Battlefield, 1962; 137(VIII):46
    - Sketch that appeared in the New York Daily Graphic, 1963; 137(VIII):47
    - Wolf Mountain Battlefield, 1963; 137(VIII):48
    - Panoramic view of Wolf Mountain battle site, (in two parts), 1963; 137(VIII):49
    - Thirteen cartridges from Wolf Mountain battle site, 1963; 137(VIII):50
    - "Crooks Hill" monument, looking west, (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):51
    - "Sioux and Snake Trough," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):52
    - Near "Conical Hill," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):53
    - Breast works on "Crooks Hill," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):54
    - "Little Breast Works," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):55
    - "Little Breast Works," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):56
    - "Little Breast Works," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):57
    - Looking east from "Little Breast Works," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):58
    - "Packers Rocks," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):59
    - Looking southeast from "Sioux and Snake Trough," (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):60
    - Bullets from "Crooks Hill," (Battle of the Rosebud), 1976; 137(VIII):61
    - Bullets, (Battle of the Rosebud), undated; 137(VIII):62
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, undated; 137(VIII):63
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, Side One, undated; 137(VIII):64
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, Side Two, undated; 137(VIII):65
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, Calvary names, undated; 137(VIII):66
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, Infantry names, undated; 137(VIII):67
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, Seventh Calvary, undated; 137(VIII):68
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, Seventh Calvary, undated; 137(VIII):69
    - West side of D.H.R. Monument, Bear's Paw Battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):70
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, undated; 137(VIII):71
    - National Cemetery Custer Battlefield National Monument, undated; 137(VIII):72
    - Springfield Rifle, Bear's Paw Battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):73
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield monuments, undated; 137(VIII):74
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield, looking down Snake Creek, undated; 137(VIII):75
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield, looking southwest, undated; 137(VIII):76
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield, looking northeast, undated; 137(VIII):77
    - Bear's Paw Battlefield, looking southeast, undated; 137(VIII):78
    - Montana state highway historical marker, 1961; 137(VIII):79
    - Artifacts from Bear's Paw Battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):80
    - Artifacts from Bear's Paw Battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):81
    - Fired cartridges, undated; 137(VIII):82
    - Artifacts from Gordon Pouliot's collection, Bear's Paw Battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):83
    - Chief Joseph's camp at 1900 (copy), undated; 137(VIII):84
    - Fort C.J. Smith (copy), undated; 137(VIII):85
    - A copy of "War Scenes" drawn by Peo-Peop Tholekt, undated; 137(VIII):86
    - Artifacts, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):87
    - Looking east, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):88
    - Location of Nez Perce fortifications, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):89
    - Relics from Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):90
    - Relics from Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):91
    - Cannon ball, similar to those used at Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):92
    - Winchester Model 1866 Saddle Ring, undated; 137(VIII):93
    - Head of a Nez Perce monument, undated; 137(VIII):94
    - Nez Perce shaft, undated; 137(VIII):95
    - Looking north from the Nez Perce shaft, undated; 137(VIII):96
    - Sign near Soldier Pit, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):97
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw relics, undated; 137(VIII):98
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw relics, undated; 137(VIII):99
    - 36 relics from Battle of the Bear's Paw battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):100
    - Relics of the Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):101
    - 0.45 - 70 cartridges fired by the 5th mounted infantry, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):102
    - Cartridges from cannon position, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):103
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw, relics, undated; 137(VIII):104
    - Relics from troop position, undated; 137(VIII):105
    - Five relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):106
    - Looking northwest to Nez Perce shaft, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):107
    - Cluster of stakes, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):108
    - Looking north to troop positions and Nez Perce Positions, undated; 137(VIII):109
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw battlefield, undated; 137(VIII):110
    - Possible location of the 4.62 inch Napoleon gun, Battle of the Bear's Paw, n.d, undated; 137(VIII):111
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):112
    - Relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, 1961; 137(VIII):113
    - Relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, 1961; 137(VIII):114
    - Relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, 1961; 137(VIII):115
    - Paper liners, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):116
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):117
    - Battle of the Bear's Paw relics, undated; 137(VIII):118
    - Enlargements of relics from Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):119
    - Enlargements of relics from Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):120
    - Relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):121
    - Relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):122
    - Iron buckle-ring, undated; 137(VIII):123
    - Relics, Battle of the Bear's Paw, undated; 137(VIII):124